IGBOKWE JOSHUA CHIDIEBERE

Phone no: +2347017892771, **E-mail**: joshdash.ji@gmail.com

PROFILE

Computer Engineering major with a passion to contribute to the digital and data world in IT through standard professional values, concepts and ethical practices. I believe my fast learning abilities, commitment to succeed, relevant studies and relevant skills with Driven experience in web development and artificial intelligence would be a perfect fit in this organization.

EDUCATION

2014-2018 Kwame Nkrumah University of Science & Technology, Kumasi

BSc. Computer Engineering (Second class upper division 2:1)

Key skills gained:

- Advanced problem solving skills
- Intermediate understanding of embedded systems and database
- Designing and programming AVR Micro controller using Atmel studio
- Ability to work with a team and produce outstanding result
- Proficiency in HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and Python

Notable modules:

 Software Engineering, Object Oriented Programming, Secure Network Systems, Robotics and Computer Vision, Embedded Systems, Database and Information Retrieval, Data Structure and Algorithms.

2007-2013 Infant Jesus Academy, Asaba

West African Senior School Certificate Examination (WASSCE)

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Purple Mecury NIG. CO, Anambra state, Nigeria

Founder and Owner – August 2020 - Till Date

- Food and Beverage company, founded to bridge gap to accessible drinkable water in the community
- Provide Managerial and technical assistant

Tydacomm Ltd, Lagos state, Nigeria

National Youth Service - December 2018- October 2019

Key responsibilities

- Dedicated network planning using Mentum Planning and MapInfo
- Assisting in maintenance of company network and IT infrastructure

Achievement

- Succeeded in designing and building a functional mini-ERP with python Django
- Ability to work with a team and produce outstanding result

Kommey Tech Computer Engineering, Kumasi, Ghana

Summer Internship – June 2017- August 2017

Key responsibilities

- Designated team leader in the designing of an Automated Aerosol
- Coding and programming AVR micro controller using Atmel studio
- Designed the Schematic of the Aerosol using Eagle

Achievement

- Succeeded in designing a working prototype of the Aerosol
- Ability to work with a team and produce outstanding result

Woliwo Microfinance Bank, Anambra State, Nigeria

2015, 2016 – summer breaks

- Worked in the IT department
- Provided technical assistant
- Filing and documenting minutes of meeting

PROJECTS AND LEADERSHIP

Jamly Africa

Django/React Project 2020/2021

This project totally automated the process of getting your business up and running online, with a tailored domain and at little or no cost.

- Team lead of a group 3 members
- Designed and developed a unique user friendly frontend UI

Automatic Dam Shutter

Final year Engineering Project 2017/2018

This project totally automated the system of dam opening and closing based on the water level in the dam.

- Appointed Team leader of a group 3 members
- Designed and developed the relevant schematics and program using eagle and Arduino respectively
- Developed befitting skeleton for the project demo with the team

SIRA

Software Engineering Module Project 2016/2017

This application allows students download PDF documents necessary for their courses (only available to Kwame Nkrumah University).

- Appointed Team leader of a group 10 members
- Followed an Iterative SDLC Model
- Designed and developed the front end of the Application

Assistant Sanitary Prefect

Infant Jesus Academy 2012 - 2013

Assistant Class Captain

Infant Jesus Academy 2010

PERSONAL PROJECTS

- Developed an application for a Wig Vendor
- Travel Application (Restaurants, lodging and Attractions)
- An ecommerce app to sell used or newish gadget

SKILLS

Computer: C, C++, C#, HTML5, CSS, React, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Django, Python, Java for Android Studio. Nodejs

Proficient in the use Microsoft office tools including word, Excel, PowerPoint and Projects.

Languages: English (fluent), Igbo (Fluent)

REFERENCES

References are available on request